Guide to the Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks, 1850s-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University, Durham, N.C., USA
- American Cookbooks 1950s, 10
  - National Presto Cooker Recipe Book, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0094)
    Note: tips on canning, catalog of Presto pots, parts list
  - No-Sew Stainless Steel Poultry Lacer, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0095)
    Product: no-sew fowl lacer
    Note: chicken-shaped pamphlet with recipe for poultry dressing on back
  - Tested Recipes: Waterless Cooking for Better Meals for Better Health, 1956 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0096)
    Product: Aluminum Cookware
    Note: color illustrations, includes tips on caring for aluminum cookware
  - You Will Enjoy Easier, Tastier Cooking with Your New Set of Modern Stainless Steel Cookware, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0097)
    Company: Stainless Steel Cookware
  - 50 New Food Ideas that Start with Borden's Wej-Cut Cream Cheese, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0098)
    Product: Wej-Cut cheese
  - 50 Good Food Ideas that Start with Borden's 4 Varieties of Wej-Cut Brand Cream Cheese, 1951 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0099)
  - 641 Tested Recipes from the Sealtest Kitchens, 1954 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0100)
  - Borden's Treasure Chest of Wonderful Premiums, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0101)
    Note: not a recipe book, booklet of knick-knacks offered at a discount with Borden's labels
  - Carnation Sour Cream Cooking, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0103)
    Product: Carnation sour cream
  - Carnation's Failure-Proof Recipes, 1957 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0104)
    Note: color illustrations, ad for 'Burns and Allen' TV program on back
  - Cookies Made With Pet Evaporated Milk, circa 1954 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0106)
  - Cooking with Nonfat Dry Milk Solids, 1952 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0107)
  - Dairy Treats, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0108)
  - Delightful Ways to Serve Cottage Cheese, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0109)
  - Desserts Plain and Fancy, 1952 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0111)
    Product: Carnation condensed milk
    Note: includes clippings of other recipes
  - Dollar Dinners Made Easy with Dairy Foods, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0112)
  - Everyday Foods for 2 or 4 or 6, 1952 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0113)
    Note: by Mary Lee Taylor
  - Family Fare and Party Fixings, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0115)
    Product: Borden cream cheese
  - Favorite Carnation Recipes by Freda De Knight, circa 1951 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0116)
    Note: foreword by Mary Blake
  - Favorite Italian American Dishes, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0117)
    Company: Sealtest Kitchens
    Product: Sealtest cottage cheese
  - Favorite Velveeta Dishes, 1954 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0118)
  - Fun and Fancy, 1957 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0119)
  - Grand Ole Opry Country Cook Book with the Stars' Own Recipes, 1957 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0120)
    Note: celebrity photographs and recipes
  - Knudsen Recipes, 1955 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0122)
  - Magic of Milk: 150 Dairy Dish and Milk Drink recipes, circa 1910s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0123)
  - Milnot's Favorite Recipes, circa 1955 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0126)
    Company: Milnot Company
    Product: Milnot dairy vegetable blend (milk substitute)
  - New Ideas for Tasty Meals with Recipes for 2 or 4, by Mary Lee Taylor, 1954 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0127)
  - New Quick Trick from the Kraft Kitchen, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0128)
    Product: Kraft Velveeta
    Note: wrapper recipe
  - Party Recipes Made with Starlac, 'The Heart of Milk', circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0129)
    Product: Starlac dry milk
  - Philly Dip Party Handbook, 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0131)
  - Quick Modern Recipes with Rich Old-Fashioned Goodness, 1956 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0132)
    Company: H. C. Moores Company
    Product: Instant Pream Dairy Product for Coffee
    Note: cartoon housewife, color photographs, recipes
  - Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0134)
    Company: Bartholomay Dairy
    Product: Dairylea products
  - Short Cuts to Delicious Meals for 2 or 4 or 6, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0135)
  - So Good--So Easy to Make Recipes by Mary Lee Taylor for 2 or 4 or 6, 1951 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0136)
  - Sour Cream Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0137)
  - Starring Cheese, 1954 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0138)
  - Start Cooking with a Golden Spoon, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0139)
    Note: includes offer for golden serving set
  - Del Monte Dried Fruit Family Cook Book, 1959 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0144)
    Product: Del Monte dried fruit
  - Elegant But Easy Recipes with California Ripe Olives, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0145)
    Product: olives
  - Florida Citrus Fare, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0147)
    Product: Florida citrus fruits
    Note: color cover, black-and-white photographs inside
  - Fresh Pears (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0150)
    Note: Pamphlet, color and black-and-white photographs of food, color drawing of boy, pear slicer offer
  - Fruit Cocktails with Pineapple from Hawaii, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0151)
    Company: Rite-Way Food Store
    Product: Pineapple from Hawaii
  - Garden of the Setting Sun Date Recipes, 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0152)
    Company: Garden of the Setting Sun
    Product: Garden of the Setting Sun Dates
  - Holiday Cranberry Dishes, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0154)
  - How to Diet Delightfully with Diet Delight Brand Foods, 1951 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0156)
    Product: Diet Delight Canned Fruit
    Note: Color illustrations and photographs, recipes
  - Musselman's Pennsylvanian Dutch Recipe Book, 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0158)
    Company: C. H. Musselman Company
    Product: Musselman Apple Sauce
    Note: Story of the Pennsylvania Dutch, black-and-white photographs, recipes
  - Recipes for the Meat Course with Pineapple from Hawaii, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0159)
  - Salads with Pineapple from Hawaii, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0160)
  - Welcome to the Home of Dole Pineapple Products, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0161)
    Product: Dole pineapple
    Note: black-and-white photographs of pineapple processing
  - 14 Easy-to-Make Dessert Recipes, 1952 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0164)
  - Better Meals with Gel-Cookery, circa 1952 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0165)
    Product: sparkling unflavored gelatine
    Note: budget recipes for main dishes, salads, and desserts
  - Fast and Fancy for Dessert, 1955 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0168)
  - Gel-Cookery Recipe Book, 1957 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0169)
  - Good Looking Cooking: A Guide to the Use of Unflavored Gelatine for Students, 1957 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0170)
    Note: color drawings, information on uses and health benefits of gelatine
  - Meal Planning for the Sick and Convalescent with Menus and Recipes, 1958 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0171)
  - Now! You Can Make Perfect Custard Flavor Dessert, 1950 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0172)
  - Royal Circus of Desserts, circa 1950s (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0173)
    Note: cartoon illustrations, circus motif
  - Royal Festival, 1955 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0174)
  - You Don't Have to Cook It!, 1953 (Box A22, Item 1950sA-0176)
    Product: Royal instant pudding
  - Aunt Jemima's Magical Recipes, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0177)
    Product: Aunt Jemima pancake mix
    Note: color illustrations, includes the story of Aunt Jemima
  - Daisy Dean's Famous Ten-Minute Fritos Recipes, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0179)
    Company: Frito Company
    Product: Frito corn chips
    Note: back cover features the Frito Kid
  - How to Run a Successful Party for Youths from 3 to 20, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0181)
    Company: DCA, Awrey Bakeries
    Product: DCA donuts
    Note: includes games, tips on serving donuts, nutritional information
  - Old-Fashioned Eating Pleasure, 1958 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0183)
    Company: Pepperidge Farm Inc.
    Product: Pepperidge Farm bread
    Note: includes photographvisit to factory, driving instructions
  - Pepperidge Farm Patty Shell Recipes, circa 1959 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0184)
    Product: Pepperidge Farm Patty Shells
  - Prince Golden Macaroni Recipes, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0185)
    Product: Prince pasta
  - Quick 'n' Easy Riceland Rice Sauce Pan Meals and Super Skillet Suppers, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0186)
  - Thomas' English Muffin Recipes, 1955 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0187)
    Company: S. B. Thomas, Inc.
    Product: Thomas' English Muffins
  - Vermont Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0188)
    Product: Maltex and Maypo cereals
  - Kitchen Secrets and Short Cuts, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0189)
  - Know Your Foods, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0190)
    Note: nutritional charts
  - Metropolitan Cook Book, 1953 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0191)
  - Around the World' Cook Book, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0192)
    Company: Kalamazoo Stove & Furnace Company
    Product: Kalamazoo stoves
    Note: folkloric drawings
  - 1954 Westinghouse Refrigerators Recipes…Care…Use, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0193)
  - All About Your New General Electric Refrigerator, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0194)
  - Amana Complete Guide to Food Freezing, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0195)
    Note: Oversize, food group charts
  - America Cooks: Favorite Recipes from North, South, East, West, 1952 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0196)
    Note: ethnic caricatures on the front cover
  - Book of Instructions and Recipes for Your New Hotpoint Refrigerator, 1950 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0197)
  - Cooking Suggestions, 1959 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0198)
    Company: RobertShaw Controls Company
    Product: RobertShaw Flame Master oven control
    Note: includes baking chart
  - Delicious Frozen Dishes Made in the Crosley Shelvador, 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0199)
    Company: Crosley Radio Corporation
    Product: Crosley Shelvador refrigerator
    Note: center-fold ad for refrigerator, photograph of company headquarters
  - Electric Cooking with Your Kenmore: Recipes and Instructions, 1957 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0200)
    Product: Kenmore ranges
  - Getting to Know Your New Frigidaire Thrifty-30 Electric Range, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0201)
    Product: Frigidaire range
  - Gibson Electric Refrigerator Instructions and Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0202)
    Company: Gibson Company
    Product: Gibson Refrigerator
  - Gibson Refrigerator Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0203)
  - How to Enjoy Your Kook-Man barbecue Grill, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0204)
    Company: Kookman
    Product: Kookman barbecue grill
  - How to Freeze Foods, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0205)
    Note: tips on food selection, animal slaughtering, includes pamphlets 'My Freezer Day by Day' by Irma Harding, and 1951 IH owner manual
  - Instructions and Recipes: Universal Select-a-Range, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0206)
    Product: Universal Select-a-Range
    Note: black-and-white illustration, information on other Universal appliances
  - Instructions and Recipes--Speedliner Electric Ranges, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0207)
    Product: Speedliner Electric Range
  - Modern Barbecuing… How to Enjoy It, 1954 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0208)
    Company: Big Boy Manufacturing Company
    Product: Big Boy barbecues
    Note: cover photograph of screen star William Bendix,
  - Modern, Carefree Gas Cookery with Your Kenmore, 1951 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0209)
  - O'Keefe & Merritt Cook Book and Operating Instructions, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0210)
    Note: Spanish-Mexican Dishes chapter with recipe titles in Spanish
  - Robin Hood No-Sift Recipes Breads & Rolls, 1953 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0211)
    Product: ranges
  - Westinghouse Food Freezing Instruction Book, 1955 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0212)
  - Your Admiral Dual Temp Refrigerator, 1955 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0213)
    Product: Admiral dual temp refrigerator
    Note: tips on cleaning, storing food in fridge
  - Your Crosley Shelvador Refrigerator, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0214)
    Company: Crosley Appliance Division
    Product: Shelvador Refrigerator
    Note: includes pictorial instructions of how to use refrigerator
  - Alaska King Crab Culinary Creations, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0215)
    Company: Star Markets
    Product: Alaskan King Crab
  - Cattle Tattle No. 22: Grand Duchess Pizza, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0216)
    Company: Grand Duchess Steaks, Inc.
    Product: Grand Duchess steaks
  - Distinctive Dinners From Marie Gifford's Kitchen, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0218)
    Product: Armour meats
  - Feasts Made Fast with R&R Chicken, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0219)
  - Food News and Views, 1953 (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0220)
    Note: part of a series, Bulletin No. 99, June-July 1953, by Martha Logan
  - Ham--the Meat for Every Occasion, circa 1950s (Box A23, Item 1950sA-0221)
    Company: Dubuque Packing Company
    Product: Dubuque canned hams
  - Hebrew National Presents 31 Ways to Make Hot Meals Out of Hot Dogs!, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0222)
    Company: Hebrew National Kosher Sausage Company, Inc.
    Product: Hebrew National Kosher Delicatessen hot dogs
  - Marie Gifford Talks Turkey, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0224)
    Product: Armour Turkey
    Note: instructions on selecting, roasting, carving turkey
  - Meat Recipes for the Family Chef, 1951 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0225)
  - New Notes in Meat Recipes, 1957 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0226)
  - Oscar Mayer Cookout Fun, 1959 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0227)
    Company: Oscar Mayer & Company
    Product: Oscar Mayer meats
  - Plain and Fancy Ways with Eggs (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0228)
    Note: black-and-white photographs, one page with color photographs
  - Recipes for Armour Star Bacon, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0229)
    Product: Armour Star bacon
  - Treats with Tuna, 1953 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0230)
    Company: Westgate-California Tuna Packing Company
  - Uses and Preparation of Maine Sardines, 1952 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0231)
    Company: Maine Sardine Industry
    Product: Maine sardines
    Note: black-and-white and color photographs, include history of Maine sardine industry
  - Choice Recipes and Menus Using Canned Foods, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0233)
    Note: black-and-white and color illustrations, tips on menu planning
  - Dining Out in Any Language: The Menu Translator, 1956 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0234)
    Company: Crown Publishers
    Note: by Myra Waldo, dictionary for menu items in 9 European languages
  - Dutch Lunch for the Crowd, 1954 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0235)
    Company: Kroger Food Corporation
    Product: grocery store chain
    Note: tips on planning for large parties
  - Fun with Foil, 1957 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0236)
    Note: color photographs, decorations
  - Gourmet Foods Cookbook, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0237)
  - Holiday How-To with Reynolds Wrap, 1954 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0238)
    Note: cooking and decorating hints
  - How to Freeze Meat and Be Glad You Did!, 1952 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0239)
    Product: Lockerfoil, Western Lockerap freezer papers
    Note: photographs of the 'home economics laboratory.' Poor condition: fragile. Spiral bound
  - Modern Living Made Easier… The Saran Wrap Way, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0240)
    Company: Dow Chemical Company
    Product: Saran Wrap
  - My Favorite Recipes, 1958 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0241)
    Company: Mrs. Alberta Norton
    Product: personal recipes
    Note: by Mrs. Alberta Norton, 1958 'Queen of the Kitchen' at Oregon State Fair
  - New Recipes--How to Use It, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0242)
    Company: Reynolds Aluminum Company
    Note: instructions on use of aluminum foil
  - Outdoor Cooking with Reynolds Wrap, 1950 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0243)
    Note: Green cover, geared toward scouts, campers, hunters, etc., recipes
  - Outdoor Guide to Outdoor Cooking, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0244)
    Note: how to craft utensils, ovens using aluminum foil
  - Preparing foods with Reynolds Wrap pure aluminum foil, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0245)
    Note: black-and-white photographs, recipes, uses
  - 101 Tasty Miracles with Dia-Mel Dietetic Foods, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0247)
    Company: Dietetic Food Company, Inc.
    Product: Dia-Mel diet foods
    Note: includes food nutritional value charts
  - Chicken Dish Ideas by Swanson and Super-Strength Alcoa aluminum foil, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0248)
    Company: Swanson, Alcoa
    Product: Swanson Chicken and Super-Strength Alcoa Wrap
  - Cookies Galore: Home Baked are Best!, 1956 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0249)
    Product: General Foods products, Post cereals, Calumet baking powder
    Note: color and black-and-white illustrations, pictures show children making cookies
  - Frozen Desserts the Modern Way, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0250)
    Product: Standard Brands products
  - Home Meal Planner: a Key to Better Meals, 1956 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0251)
    Note: guide to meal planning, nutrition, food groups
  - Nothing But the Best! Cook Book -- Montana Products for Montana Homes, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0253)
    Company: Anaconda Copper Mining Company, Red Lodge Canning Company, Montana Products for Montana Homes, General Foods
    Product: Rocky Mountain Beer, Burr's of Butte (retail), Eddy's Bread, Baker's chocolate
    Note: glossary of cooking terms
  - Outdoor Food and Fun, 1950 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0254)
    Product: Kellogg's products
    Note: tips on eating outdoors
  - Soufflé Salads Quick and Easy, the New Fast-Frost Way, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0255)
    Product: Jell-O, Hellmann's and Best Foods mayonnaise
  - Special Diet Recipes, 1951 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0256)
    Product: Gerber cereal foods, strained vegetables, fruits, and meats
    Note: preface by nutritionist Edna Mae McIntosh
  - Standard Brands Part in Serving Good Food in Hotels, Restaurants and Institutions, 1950 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0257)
  - Funsten's Tasty-Tested Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0259)
    Company: R. E. Funsten Company
    Product: Funsten's nuts
  - Menu Magic in a Nutshell, 1950 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0260)
    Note: color illustrations, inset illustrations of walnut processing
  - New Walnut Cook Book, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0261)
    Company: Diamond Walnut Growers
  - Tas-T-Nut Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0262)
    Company: Tas-T-Nut Company
    Product: Tas-T-Nut nuts
  - 20 Wonderful Cakes Made by the New Kraft Oil Method, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0264)
  - Discover Finer Foods with Wonderful Whirl: New Golden Whirl Introductory Cookbook, circa 1953 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0266)
    Product: Whirl shortening
    Note: color pictures, pub. Date based on USPTO search
  - Frying Made Easy, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0267)
  - How to Win Compliments for Your Cooking, 1950 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0269)
  - Spry 20th Anniversary Cookbook of Old and New Favorites, 1955 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0270)
    Note: black-and-white illustrations, step by step instructions
  - Tri-Nut TV Recipe Book, circa 1956 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0271)
    Company: E. F. Drew & Company
    Product: Tri-Nut margarine
  - Winning Ways with Swiftn'ing, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0272)
    Product: Swiftn'ing lard
    Note: signed by 'Martha Logan'
  - Hamilton Beach Food Mixer Instructions and Tested recipes, circa 1950s (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0274)
    Note: black-and-white photographs and drawings, 'how-to' photographs
  - Hardwick MicroRay Cookbook, circa 1958 (Box A24, Item 1950sA-0275)
    Product: Hardwick Micro Ray stove
  - Hollywood Liquifier Recipes, 1951 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0276)
    Company: Hollywood Company
    Product: Hollywood Liquifier
  - How to be a Cake Genius with Your Sunbeam Mixmaster, 1951 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0277)
  - Kenmore Automatic Electric Roaster Instruction and Recipe Book, 1952 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0278)
    Product: Kenmore Automatic Electric Roaster
    Note: foreword by Jean Shaw, Home Economist, hints on canning
  - Kitchen-Tested Flavor-Perfect Recipes for Your New Automatic Cooker and Deep Fryer, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0279)
    Product: automatic cooker and deep fryer
  - Manning-Bowman Automatic Corn Popper No. 500, 1952 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0280)
    Product: Manning-Bowman corn popper
  - Miraculous Cooking with the Amazing New Universal Cookamatic Automatic Control, 1957 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0281)
    Product: Universal Cookamatic control
    Note: color photographs, pictures of product line
  - MixMaster Mixer Instruction and Recipe Book, 1957 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0282)
    Product: MixMaster Mixer
    Note: no pictures of women in the kitchen
  - Your Holliwood Gourmet Rotisserie Recipe Book, 1954 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0284)
    Company: Finders Manufacturing Company
    Product: Holliwood rotisserie
    Note: back cover feature line of Holliwood appliances
  - 9 Easy, Delicious Recipes for Cooking with Campbell's Tomato Soup, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0285)
    Product: Campbell tomato soup
  - Easy Ways to Good Meals: 99 Delicious Dishes Made with Campbell's Soups, 1950 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0286)
    Note: color and black-and-white pictures, meal planner guide
  - Recipes for Quantity Food Service, 1956 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0287)
    Note: color illustrations, index card format, designed for institutional kitchens
  - Recipes Using Heinz Soups, 1957 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0288)
    Product: Heinz Soups
    Note: small red, black, & white booklet with 6 recipes, descriptions of the 23 Heinz soups, and a page of soup mergers
  - Brer Rabbit's Modern Recipes for Modern Living, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0290)
  - B-Z-B Honey Cookies, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0291)
    Company: B-Z-B Honey Company
    Product: B-Z-B honey
  - Calorie Saving Recipes for Foods Sweetened Without Sugar, 1952 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0292)
    Product: Sucaryl artificial sweetener
    Note: includes sugar substitution tables
  - Famous Recipes from Old New Orleans, 1951 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0293)
    Note: tips on cooking, first aid, household cleaning
  - Flavor Magic for Your Favorite Foods, 1953 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0294)
    Company: Kraft Kitchens
    Product: Kraft jellies
    Note: indexed, color illustrations
  - Grandma's Recipes for Mother and Daughter, 1950 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0295)
    Note: Mother and daughter, black-and-white photographs (mainly food), Cook and Bake with Grandma's insert, nutrition information.
  - Mary Matthews' Time-Saver Recipes, 1955 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0296)
  - Recipes for Kitchen-Klatter No-Calorie Sweetener in the Flip-top Bottle, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0297)
    Company: Kitchen-Klatter Products Company
    Product: Kitchen-Klatter sweetener
    Note: tie-in with Kitchen-Klatter magazine
  - Recipes for Kitchen-Klatter No-Calorie Sweetener in the Flip-top Bottle, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0298)
  - Cooking with a Foreign Accent, 1954 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0299)
    Company: Pacific Telephone
    Product: telephone service
    Note: originally designed for employees' information rack
  - Food Freezing Facts, 1954 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0300)
    Note: charts for preserving, freezing
  - Home Service Cookie Treasures, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0301)
    Company: Iroquois Gas Corporation
  - Lenten Recipes, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0302)
    Company: Consolidated Gas Company of New York
  - Make the Most of Meat, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0303)
    Company: SMUD (Sacramento Municipal Utility District)
    Product: electrical service
  - Treasury of Christmas Gift and Homemaking Ideas, circa 1950s (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0304)
    Company: Rochester Gas & Electric
    Product: electrical appliances
    Note: includes appliances as gift ideas, decorating, menu suggestions
  - Crisp French Fried Onions, 1955 (Box A25, Item 1950sA-0305)